It's time for a new adventure for Doctor Who.
又到了神秘博士新探险的时候了
The Doctor, together with his friends Ben, Polly and Jamie,
博士，和他的朋友 Ben, Polly 和 Jamie 一起
defeated the insane professor Zaroff to blow up the world.
挫败了疯狂教授 Zaroff 要炸毁全世界的计划
Leaving Atlantis behind, the Doctor set course for Mars,
离开了亚特兰蒂斯，博士设定了去往火星的航向
But then the TARDIS goes wildly out of control.
但 TARDIS 开始完全失控了...
Anyone would think we got rats up here.
谁会想到这里还会有老鼠
WHO IS THAT?!
谁在那儿？
Who is it?
是谁？
The Moonbase
月球基地
《神秘博士》老版第四季第六集
(Whopix fan edit version)
(Whopix 粉丝剪辑版)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
Doctor, do something!
博士，做点什么啊！
I'm trying to!
我正努力呢
Everything back under control again.
一切又恢复掌控控之中了
Here, we're landing! Look!
我们快着陆了，看！
Oh, thank the lord for that. You know, Doctor,
I'll never ask you to do that again.
噢，感谢上天．博士，我再也不让你那么做了
There must be a reason for that.
出现这个情况肯定是有原因的
Hey, wait a mo! This doesn't look like Mars to me.
嘿，等一下！我觉得这里不像是火星
How do you know? You never seen it.
你怎么知道？你又从来没见过
No, Duchess, but I have seen pictures of the moon surface
and that's what this looks like.
是没见过，夫人．但我看过月球表面的照片，这跟那个很像啊
That's the moon?
那是月球？
Doctor, is it the moon?
博士，这是月球吗？
Oh well, you weren't too far out, were you?
Only two hundred million miles!
那个，你没有偏离多远吧，对不？不到两亿英里！
All right, let's move on - while we can.
好啦，我们继续前进吧 - 趁着还能
- What!
- Now wait a minute! You don't expect to land us
on the moon and let us fly off just like that, do you?
- 什么！ - 等一下！你不会指望把我们拉到月球，然后就马上把我们拉走吧，是吧？
Yeah, at least let us have a look around!
是啊，至少我们得四周转转
That picture canna be the moon? The moon's way up in the sky.
那个镜头不可能是月球．月球正在天上呢
Where do you think you're going?
你觉得你要去哪儿？
You're not going to tell us there is no shore leave?
你不会告诉我们没有上岸假期吧？
Oh please Doctor. The TARDIS isn't out of control or anything is it?
噢求你了，博士．TARDIS没有失控什么的吧？
Oh no, no, no. Just a bumpy landing. That's all
没没没，只是着陆有点颠簸，仅此而已
Yeah?
嘢？
Well, if you must go ashore... only half an hour.
好吧，如果你们要上岸...只有半个小时
- Right.
- Superb
- 好  - 太棒了
You can't go ashore like that!
You need space suits, there's no atmosphere out there.
你们不能就这样上岸啊！你们需要太空服，外面没有空气
Come on, there's some in the chest.
来，箱子里有几件
Maybe we'll meet the old man in the moon.
也许我们能碰到月球上最老的人
You won't meet anybody mate if you don't get some gear on.
如果你不穿上一些装备，你就碰不到任何人了
What? Oh aye.
什么？是啊
Hey, look at this.
嘿，看看这个
Its deserted.
这里很荒凉
Yeah, I don't think I like it.
是啊，我觉得我不喜欢它
Hey, what do we need this great clogs for?
嘿，我们需要这个大木块做什么？
Try a little jump.
试着轻轻跳一下
All right.
好啊
Careful! One tear in that space suit and you'll suffocate.
小心点！太空服破一个口子你们就会窒息
Come on, it's easy.
来吧，很容易的
Look out, here I come.
小心，我来了
Where's he gone?
他去哪儿了？
Over there.
在那边
What on Earth? Look!
这是什么？看！
Blimey! What is it?
啊呀，那是什么？
Doctor, what is it?
博士，它是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
Hey, I can see Jamie, there he is.
嘿，我看见 Jamie 了，他在那儿
Hey, there's somebody coming out.
嘿，有人出来了
Come on, let's go.
快来，我们走
And... Jules, you take over.
然后... Jules，你接手
There must be some source to this infection.
这种感染一定有某种来源
Look, then get the lads in here and tell them what's happening.
听着，就把小伙子们都叫进来，告诉他们发生了什么事
Get them on the blower would you, Nils.
让他们在鼓风机上，可以吗，Nils？
Hello. Where did you lot spring from? /
你好，你们是从哪里蹦出来的？
Don't tell me the shuttle rocket arrived already?
别告诉我穿梭火箭已经到了？
No, it hasn't.
不，它没有
There was another one with them, sir.
Bob taken him along to the Medical unit.
他们还有一个人，头儿．Bob 已经将他带到医务室去了
He's all right. He's just knocked himself out or something.
他没大碍，只是自己撞到什么东西上了
Oh no, if we haven't got enough troubles already.
噢不，好像我们麻烦还不够多似的
We don't want to cause you any trouble.
Just let us collect our young friend and we'll be off.
我们不会给你们添麻烦的．让我们去接我们的年轻朋友，然后我们就离开
Hey, not so fast.
嘿，别这么着急
Please let me go and see Jamie.
请让我走，我要去看看 Jamie
I will take you there Mademoiselle. If you come with me.
我带你去那里，小姐，请跟我来
All right, young lady. You can carry on.
好吧，年轻女士，你可以去
This way.
这边
Well, you know what this place is?
对了，你知道这是什么地方吗？
Well, it looks like some sort of weather control centre.
这个嘛，看起来像是某种天气控制中心
Ah, yes. And that's the thing with which
you control the weather. That's the culprit then.
啊，是了，那就是用来控制天气的东西．那它就是罪魁祸首了
Hey?
嗯？
Hmmm. That's what gave us a bumpy landing.
嗯，就是那东西让我们着陆时颠簸
- Hm-Hmm.
- I see
- 嗯哼  - 我明白了
The gravitron controls the tides, the tides controls the weather.
引力创控制潮汐，潮汐就控制天气
And from this console we can plot it all on that map.
然后从这个控制台，我们可以将这一切绘制在那个地图上
Simple, eh?
简单不？
Yeah, very simple.
是，非常简单
It's Jim. Quick Francois, take over.
是 Jim．快点，Francois，你接手
International Space Control Earth calling
Weather Control Moon - come in please.
国际空间控制中心地球站呼唤天气控制中心月球站 - 听到请回答
Moonport - standing by.
月球基地 正在待命
Ever seen anything like that before, Doctor?
以前见过这样的情况吗，博士？
Hobson here.
我是 Hobson
What's happening up there? The hurricane you were guiding
is now 45 degrees off course. It's threatening Hawaii.
上面发生什么事了？你所引导的飓风现在偏离了45度．它正在威胁夏威夷
One of my men were taken ill. We're operational again now.
我的一个手下生病了．我们已恢复运作
The controller would like to know the cause of the illness.
控制员想知道疾病的原因
Yes, so would we. We now have three men down
是，我们也想知道．我们现在已经有三个人倒下了
with this mysterious virus in the past few hours
- including the Doctor.
都是因为这种神秘的病毒，在过去的几小时内倒下的 -- 包括医生本人
One moment please. Stand by for further instructions.
稍等一下，请等候进一步通知
Just hang on for another couple of minutes lads.
We better hear what the great Mr. Rinberg has to say.
再等几分钟，小伙子们．我们最好听听伟大的林伯格先生有什么话要说
We're being monitored again.
我们又被监听了
Monitored?
监听？
Someone, not too far away from the base,
is listening to every word we say.
某个人，正在离基地不远的地方，监听着我们说的每一个字
"Moonbase, Moonbase, come in Moonbase. "
月球基地，月球基地，收到请回话
Still standing by.
仍旧等待
If you radio information about this virus,
如果你将这种病毒的信息传送过来
we can do our best to identify it and suggest treatment.
我们可以尽最大努力识别它，并给出治疗建议
I demand to speak to Rinberg.
我请求与Rinberg通话
The controller is busy - I'm sorry. Over and out.
控制员正忙，对不起．结束通话
That whole conversion was monitored by someone or something.
整个通话过程都被监听了，被某个人或某种东西
Oh, never mind about that now.
That Rinberg fellow won't talk to you.
哦，现在别管那个了．Rinberg 那个家伙不会和你说话的
How can we trace down this mystery illness
with the Doctor himself down with it.
我们怎样才能追查出这种神秘的疾病的来源呢，我们的医生都被他干倒了
We better get out of these things and see how Jamie is.
Perhaps I can be of help in the sick bay now.
我们最好先出身去看看 Jamie 怎么样了．也许现在我可以在医务室帮上点忙
Anything you can do... Bob!
能做些什么就做吧...Bob！
Yes, Mr Hobson?
什么，Hobson 先生？
Show them to the Medical unit will you?
带他们去医务室，可以吗？
Yes, of course. Now, if you will come this way, please?
好的，当然．现在，你们来这边吧，请
Yes. Thank you.
好．谢谢你
Well, you all heard the position. We don't know
what this infection is and how it got into the base
好了，当前的情况你们都听到了．我们不知道这种传染病是什么，是怎么进到基地的
but I want you all to take extra precautions
while this emergency is on
但当前还是紧急状态，我期望你们都千万小心
We may be short-handed for quite a while.
我们在相当一段时间内可能会人手不足
Is this how its goes, Doctor?
它就是这样运作的吗，博士？
Yes, that's right. Then, this unit automatically
controls the pulse, the temperature and the breathing.
对，就是那样．然后，这个设备会自动控制脉搏、体温和呼吸
A sort of electronic Doctor.
像是个电子医生
Yes.
对
And it even give you medicines too?
而且它还能给配药吗？
Yes. It will do very nearly everything.
是的，它差不多能干所有事了
How do you think he is, Doctor?
你觉得他状态怎么样，博士？
Oh, he's not too bad. He's a bit concussed
and feverish but he'll be all right with rest.
哦，并不差．他有点脑震荡和发烧，但休息一下就没事了
The Piper! The McCrimmon Piper! Don't let him get me!
风笛手！McCrimmon家的风笛手！别让他抓走我！
Piper?
风笛手？
Some legend of his clan. As far, as I can make out
他们家族的某个传说．据我现在琢磨出来的结论
this piper appears to a McCrimmon just before he dies.
这个风笛手会在 McCrimmon 家族的人死就会出现
Has this phantom piper appeared to Jamie yet?
那这个幽灵风笛手在 Jaime 面前出现了吗？
You don't believe it, do you?
你不会相信这个吧，会吗？
No, but he does. It's important to him.
不信，但他信，这对他很重要
He keeps asking us to keep the piper away from him.
他不停地要求我们不让那个风笛手靠近他
Good. We can see if we can do just that.
好，我们看看能不能做到
Well, carry on Nurse.
好了，继续吧护士
Well, at least I try to help. There's a ward full of sick men
and no doctor. Somebody got to do something.
嗯，至少我会尽量帮忙．这里满是病人，没有医生，得有人做点什么
I wonder who this is?
咦，这是谁？
Don't get too near. Have a look on his chart.
别太近了，看看他的记录
That's a good idea.
这是个好注意
It's Dr. Evans.
是 Evans 医生
Oh, yes. The station doctor. He was the first one to get it.
哦，对，站内的医生．他是第一个得病的
He looks one of the worst.
他是看起来情况最严重的
There's something about this epidemic
that I... I just don't understand.
对于这个流行病，有一些是我...不能理解的
It's not like a real disease at all! It's almost like...
看着就不像一种真正的疾病，完全像是...
Not real! What more do you want?
不是真正的！你还想要多真？
I don't know. But there are certain signs and symptoms
which don't add up.
我不知道，但这里有一些体征和症状相互矛盾
Ben, I want you to go to the control room and keep an eye on things.
Ben，我要你到控制室去，盯着点
But how?
怎么盯？
Give a hand, do anything but keep your eyes and ears open.
帮帮忙什么的，做什么都行，不过眼睛要放亮点
Right.
好
There's something very wrong here. Something very wrong indeed.
这里有些事情非常不对劲，真的非常不对劲
Still up, Nobby. Why not take a rest. Go and get some sleep.
还没睡啊，Nobby, 为什么不休息一下，去睡一下吧
Oh, How can I rest with that thing up the spout.
You know the score as well as I do.
噢，有了这事儿我这么还能睡得着啊，你跟我一样清楚现在的状态
Five units off centre and we lift half London into space!
偏离中心五个单位，半个伦敦就被抬到空中了
Five more and the Atlantic water level goes up three feet!
再偏五个单位，大西洋的水平面就得上升三尺！
Rinberg don't understand the pressure we're under.
Rinerg 并不理解我们当前的压力
Hey you! What do you thinking you are doing?! Skulking here?
嘿你！你在干什么呢！在这里躲懒吗?
Just wondering if I can help, sir.
只是看看有什么能帮上忙的，先生
Well, how can you help?
哦，你能帮什么忙？
We can do with an extra pair of hands - he can help me.
我们这边需要多几个人手 - 他可以来帮我
Well, keep him away from me, that's all.
行，别让他在我这里晃悠就行了．
All right, I'll go and lie down. Call me if anything happens.
好了，我走了，去躺躺．如果有任何事就叫我
Yes, of course.
好的，没问题
Oh, by the way, there were two more of those momentary drops
in air pressure while I was on.
哦，顺便说一下，我在这里的时候又出现过两次短暂的气压下降
I have put them in the log.
我都记在日志里面了
Right.
好的
What is that?
那是什么？
Shhhh, it's all right Polly. It's only me.
We don't want to wake everybody up do we?
嘘，没事的 Polly．就我一个．我们不想吵醒每一个人吧
You look if you can do with some sleep yourself.
你看起来也需要睡一会儿
I'm all right.
我没事
What have you got there?
你那边发现什么了吗？
Oh, I been doing a little investigation.
哦，我做了一点调查
A piece of silver paper. What is it?
一小块银箔，是什么东西？
I don't know.
我不知道
What's happened?!
什么情况？
Oh, it's nothing. It probably just a changeover in the time cycle.
哦，没事．只是人工昼夜交替而已
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Oh, you see - it's rather interesting really
哦，你看，这真的很有意思
you see on the moon, they have a fortnight of days
and a fortnight of nights.
你看看月球，他们有长达１４天的白天和１４天的黑夜
Well?
是吗？
Well, it's oblivious isn't it? They have to
make their own day and night artificially up there
是啊，这很明显啊是不？他们这里就不得不靠人工制造白天和黑夜
Or it would upset their own biological time clock.
否则他们的生物钟就会紊乱
Their what?
他们的什么？
They won't know if they were coming or going. Get it?
他们就不知道该起床还是睡觉了，明白了吗？
Yes.
哦
Clever girl. QED. That's why it's dark up here.
聪明. 证明完毕．这就是为什么现在这里黑了
Oh, I see what you mean. Yes, of course. How stupid of me.
哦，我明白你什么意思了．对了，当然．我真是太蠢了
Of course along the control centre it's probably broad daylight.
当然了在控制中心那边可能一直都是白天
Polly, you wouldn't be making fun of me would you?
Polly, 你不是在逗我吧，是吗？
No.
不！
Dr. Evans.
Evans 医生
The hand. No, don't touch me. No. The silver hand.
手，不，不要碰我．不，银色的手
Doctor, is he...
博士，他是不是．．．
Yes, I'm afraid he is.
是的，恐怕他是
What are we gone to do?
那我们该做什么？
What does he means by the silver hand.
I better report this to Mr. Hobson.
他说＂银色的手＂是什么意思？我最好向 Hobson 先生报告一下
What's the matter?
什么情况？
Something just went out of that door!
什么东西从那个门跑出去了！
Nils! John!
What was it?
是什么东西？
Nothing. Nothing there.
没有，那里什么也没有
Your nerves are getting the better of you. Where's Evan's body?
你太神经过敏了．Evan 的尸体呢？
Over there.
在那边
All right, let's get it over with.
好了，让我们结束吧
Is this somebody's idea of a particularly bad joke?
这是谁开的恶意玩笑吗？
This is no joke, believe me!
这不是玩笑，相信我！
Mr. Hobson, Mr. Hobson, you are wanted!
Hobson 先生，Hobson 先生，这里需要你
Another man's collapsed at the controls
and the Gravitron has been thrown off alignment again.
控制室又有一个人倒下了，引力创也又一次跑偏了
Come on!
快来！
And you better find that Doctor's body or out you all go
- quarantine or no quarantine.
你们最好找到医生的尸体，否则你们都得出去 - 不管隔离不隔离
I don't understand what could have happened.
I must have dozed off or something
我不清楚刚才可能发生了什么，我肯定是打盹了
but one thing I am sure of
- something went out of that door just as you came in.
但有一件事我可以肯定：你进来的时候有什么东西跑出那个门去了
That body can't just have vanished.
Polly, I am going to leave you alone...
尸体不可能凭空消失的．Polly, 我得让你一个人在这里...
...just for a minute.
...就几分钟
All right.
好的
Water. Water.
水．水
I'll go and get you some.
我去给你弄点
Water!
水！
It's you.
是你
The phantom piper!
幽灵风笛手！
No!
不！
No! I'll not go with you!
不！我不跟你走！
Do you hear me, piper? No! Leave me!
你听到了没，风笛手？不，走开！
Leave me. I'll not go with you, do you hear me?
走开．我不跟你走，你听到了没？
Leave me! No, I'll not go with you!
走开！不，我不跟你走！
I'll fight you every inch of the way.
我每一步都要跟你斗
I'll not go with you.
我不跟你走
Leave me, piper.
走开，风笛手
No. Leave me. I'll not go.
不，走开，我不走
Agh!
啊
- Polly, what's happened?
- Oh, Doctor, it was horrible!
- Polly, 发生什么事了？  - 哦，博士，太吓人了
- A giant creature like a Cyberman!
- It's all right. Don't be frightened.
- 一个赛博人一样的大家伙  - 没事了，别怕
- Whatever it was, it's gone now.
- It's the... Doctor, the Cyberman was carrying a patient.
- 不管是什么，现在已经走了 - 那是...博士，那个赛博人扛着一个病人
- Cyberman? What are you talking about?
- I'm sure it was.
- 赛博人？你在说些什么？  - 我确定是
- I'll not go with you.
- It's OK. It's safe now. Take it easy.
- 我不跟你走  - 没事了，现在安全了，放松
She's right. There's another one gone.
她是对的，又有一个不见了
Sam, Jules, you've got to find these men.
They can't just disappear in a place this size.
Sam, Jules, 你们去找这几个人．他们不可能消失了，就这么点大个地方
Search every square inch, don't come back
until you find them. Now move.
每一寸都要搜到，找不到他们就不要回来．快去
Now, supposing you tell me your story? What did you see?
现在，来跟我说说你的故事？你看到了什么？
I went out to get Jamie some water,
我出去给 Jamie 倒点水
and when I came back,
I saw this giant man or creature or something,
当我回来的时候，我看到一个高大的人或者生物什么的
just going out of the door,
carrying one of the patients... like a doll.
它正走出门去，扛着一个我们的病人...像个玩偶一样
- I think it was a Cyberman.
- Forget that part. Then what?
- 我觉得那是个赛博人  - 忘了那个吧．然后呢？
Then nothing. The door shut, and then you came in.
然后没什么了．门关上了，然后你们进来了
- What do you know about all this?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
- 这一切你都知道些什么？  - 没什么，什么也不知道
We'll see about that in a minute.
我们稍后再来讨论
- This thing you saw. What was it like?
- It was enormous, and silver.
- 你看见的这个东西，它是什么样子？  - 很高大，银色外形
- It had holes in its head for eyes, like a robot.
- A robot?
- 脑袋上眼睛那个位置有洞，像个机器人一样  - 像个机器人?
But the Cybermen were all killed when Mondas blew up.
但 Mondas 爆炸的时候赛博人都死了啊
Stop this Cyberman nonsense!
别胡说赛博人那些东西了
There were Cybermen, every child knows that,
but they were destroyed ages ago!
以前是有赛博人，每个小孩子都知道．但他们几十年前就被消灭了！
（注:  赛博人初次出现于1986年，试图夺取地球，后与母星
Mondas 一起毁灭．参见04x01 第十行星 The Tenth Planet）
- So we all thought.
- That's enough.
- 我们都这么想  - 别再说了
Let's have a little calm thinking.
我们都冷静地想一想
For the past two weeks,
a complete unknown disease has appeared in the base.
过去两个星期以来，一种完全未知的疾病出现在这个基地
People drop in their tracks
and develop a black pattern on their skin.
人在工作岗位上倒下，皮肤上长出黑色的条纹
Then some of the patients disappear, right?
然后又有一些病人消失了，对不？
They can't leave the base without wearing spacesuits,
and there are no spacesuits missing. So where are they?
不穿太空服的花他们不可能离开基地，但又没有太空服丢失．那他们在哪儿？
- I must say, It does sound a little odd.
- More than a little.
- 我得说，这事听着是有一点点奇怪  - 不是一点点
I do know one thing - a new disease starts,
people disappear, and then you turn up.
我倒的确知道一件事情 - 新疾病出现，人们消失，然后你们出现了
- And you think we did it!
- Oh, come on, we haven't done a thing!
- 那你就觉得是我们干的？  - 哦，得了，我们什么也没干！
Perhaps maybe, I don't know who you are,
what you are, or where you came from,
也许吧，我也不知道你们是谁，是干什么的，从哪里来
but you can get off the moon now!
但你们现在就可以离开月球了！
- Well, that suits me fine, the sooner the better!
- No, Ben, we can't go yet.
- 好啊，正想走呢，越早越好！  - 不，Ben, 我们还不能走
- Why not? They don't want us here.
- Because there is something evil here. We must stay.
- 为什么不？他们不想让我们在这里 - 因为这里有邪恶的东西，我们必须留下来
- Evil? Don't be daft!
- Evil is what I meant.
- 邪恶？ 别犯傻了！   - 邪恶．我说的就是这个
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred the most terrible things.
宇宙中有些角落会孕育出最可怕的东西
Things which act against everything
that we believe in. They must be fought.
这些东西会跟我们所信仰的一切作对．我们必须跟他们斗争
This disease, for instance. It isn't really
a disease at all, but I can help you with it.
举例来说，这个疾病，其实并不是一种病．但我可以帮助你们
You'll see. I'll find the cause for you.
你会看到，我会帮你们找到原因
- Will you, indeed?
- Yes, certainly. I just need to examine a few things. That's all.
- 会吗，真的？ - 当然．我需要先检验几样东西，仅此而已
- It should be simple.
- Well, I'm not sure.
- 那很简单  - 嗯，我不太确定
I'll give you just one Earth-day cycle to find the cause.
我给你一个地球日的时间来寻找原因
- Earth what?
- 24 hours.
- 地球什么？  - ２４小时
- But that's no time at all.
- It's all you're going to get.
- 但这时间也太短了吧  - 你们只有这些时间
Then you get off the moon, with this bloke here.
然后你们就离开月球，带着这个家伙
- You can't move him! He's very ill.
- We accept.
- 你不能乱动他，他病得很厉害  - 我们接受
Now tell me, you have pathological equipment here, yes?
现在说说，你们这里有病理分析设备吧？
Yes. Evans was working on an extensive research project.
It's all in here.
有．Evans 之前在做一个扩展研究项目．东西都在这里
It's quite a small unit. We're not equipped
to deal with a full-scale epidemic.
是一套小型设备，我们并没有针对大规模传染病的配置
- Do you think you can manage?
- Yes. I think I can.
- 你觉得你能搞定吗？ - 是的，我觉得我能
Right. I'll leave you to it. Don't forget - 24 hours.
好，我就不打扰你了．不要忘了 - ２４小时
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- We'll start with this one.
- 你打算怎么做，博士？ - 我们从这个开始
- Are you really a medical doctor?
- Yes, I think I was once
- 你真是一个医学博士吗？  - 是的，我想我曾经做过
Polly, I think I took a degree once, in Glasgow.
Polly, 我记得我拿到了学位，在格拉斯哥
1888, I think. Lister. Hold that for me, will you?
1888年，没记错的话. 李斯特．帮我把住这里，行吗
（约瑟夫-李斯特 英国外科医生，外科手术消毒技术的发明者和推广者）
- Oh!
- All right. He's quite unconscious.
- 噢！  - 没事，他完全没意识了
It's all right, Jamie. It's all right.
You're going to get better but you must lie still.
没事的，Jamie, 没事．你会好起来的，但你必须要躺好
What is this place? Is it the home of the piper?
这是什么地方？这是风笛手的家吗？
No, we're on the moon. You know, the moon up in the sky.
不，我们在月球上．你知道吗，天上的月亮
No, I can't be alive.
不，我不可能还活着
I've just seen the piper.
我刚才看见了风笛手
The piper! I knew!
风笛手！我就知道！
Polly! What's happened?
Polly! 发生了什么事？
Polly.
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
没有，什么都没有
- Isn't there any clue at all?
- No. It's a complete blank.
- 一点线索也没有吗？  - 没有，完全的空白
All the tests are negative. As far as I can see,
this whole ridiculous place is sterile.
所有测试结果都是阴性的．就我所看到的来说，这整个破地方都是无菌的
We'll have to tell Mr Hobson, I suppose.
- 我们不得不跟 Hobson 先生说了，我想
I don't like it very much. I simply don't understand it.
我不喜欢这个结果．我就是想不明白
Doctor, it couldn't possibly have
anything to do with Lister, could it?
博士，这会不会跟李斯特有关，可能吗？
- Lister?
- Well, I mean, you did say...
- 李斯特  - 这样，我是说，你不是说
that you took your degree in Glasgow in 1888.
你1888年在格拉斯哥拿到了学位
That's an awfully long time from now, 2070, whatever it is.
那可是一段好长的时间了，现在是2070年了
Polly, are you suggesting that
I'm not confident to carry out these tests?
Polly, 你是不是想说我并没有能力进行这些检测？
No, No, I'm just wondering if there was anything
that Joseph Lister didn't know in 1888
不，不，我只是在想会不会有些什么东西是约瑟夫-李斯特在1888年不知道的
- that might help you now.
- Ssh! Somebody's coming!
- 说不定可以帮上你  - 嘘，有人来了！
It's Mr Hobson. Out for blood - ours. Look busy! Quick!
是 Hobson 先生． 去拿血样 - 我们的．装作忙碌，快！
That's the third person to disappear in the past few hours.
这是在过去几个小时内消失的第三个人了
- It's completely illogical.
- Do you mind?
- 这完全没逻辑  - 可以吗？
Would you mind standing away from the door
and allowing it to close? The slides. The dust!
你别站在门边可以吗，让门可以关上？检测片. 灰尘！
It must be you people.
We've got some straight talking to do, you and I.
肯定是你的人．我们得好好谈一谈了，你跟我
- Polly. Another boot.
- Do you hear me?
- Polly, 再来一下  - 你听到我的话了吗？
- This is extraordinary. Look here.
- Excuse me, please.
- 这真是不寻常啊，看这里  - 借过一下，请
Excuse me. We ARE trying to help you.
对不起，我们正在试图帮你忙呢
- Help? Is that what you call it? You can all get off the moon now.
- No, wait a minute. You said...
- 帮忙？你管这个叫帮忙？你们现在就可以离开月球了 - 不，等一下，你说过...
- I don't care what I said!
- Ah!
- 我不管我说过什么！  - 哈！
- Have you found something?
- I think perhaps I have.
- 你发现什么了吗？  - 我想也许我发现了
Yes, I may be onto something, but I must have some room.
是的，我可能找到点头绪，但我必须得有空间
How can I work under these conditions? Now, please,
come along. Outside. I'm trying to work in here!
在这种条件下我怎么工作？ 现在，请过来，外面去．我在这里尽力工作呢
- Ben, see that they stay outside.
- Did you mean that?
- Ben, 确保他们待在外面  - 你真的吗？
- What?
- You've found something?
- 什么？  - 你发现了点什么？
Oh, Polly, I only wish I had.
哦，Polly, 我也期望我是
- Coffee? Sugar?
- Hello, Doctor. Thank you.
- 要咖啡不？ 糖？  - 你好，博士．谢谢你
- It's very hot. Doctor, what about you?
- Thank you, Polly.
- 这很热. 博士，你要吗？ - 谢谢你，Polly
Doctor, as I was saying, you've had your chance.
You come up with absolutely nothing.
博士，如我之前说过的，给过你们机会了．但你的结果是完全的空白
Don't touch him!
别碰他！
Let me look.
我看看
Charlie and you, Ben, give us a hand
to get him into the medical unit.
Charlie 和你 Ben, 搭一下手，把他弄到医务室去
Try not to touch his skin.
尽量不要碰到他的皮肤
Don't drink that! It's the sugar!
不要喝那个！是糖！
Don't you see? That's why the disease doesn't affect everyone.
你明白了吗？那就是为什么这个病没有感染每一个人
It's the sugar. Not everyone takes it.
是糖有问题，不是每个人都加糖
Don't touch it.
别碰它
- What are you doing?
- Just be patient.
- 你在干什么  - 耐心点
Just as I thought.
正如我所料想的
A large neurotropic virus.
一种大型的神经病毒
- Like the space plague?
- No.
- 就像太空瘟疫? - 不
（注: 太空瘟疫是科幻小说 Highways in Hiding 所描绘的一种疾病,
初始表象是手指脚趾硬化，然后扩散到四肢以及全身. 此小说的简略版名称即为"太空瘟疫")
It's a large infective agent that only attacks the nerves.
这是一种大型感染剂，只攻击神经系统
That's why these patients got these lines
appear on faces and hands.
这就是为什么那些病人脸上手上会出现那些条纹
It follows the course of the nerves under the skin.
它沿着皮下的神经脉络走动
That's _ it well. But how did it get in here?
但它怎么进入这个地方的？
It is the Cybermen. I believe they have
deliberately infected the base.
是赛博人．我相信是他们故意感染了这个基地
My men have searched every square of the base.
我的人搜索了这个基地的每一寸地方
There's no space to hide a cat, let alone a Cyberman.
这个地方连只猫都没地方躲，更别说赛博人了
Anyhow, how did they get in?
不管怎么说，他们怎么进来的
- One moment.
- What is it?
- 等一下  - 什么
- You say you searched all the base?
- Yes. What of it?
- 你说你们把整个基地搜遍了？ - 是啊，怎么？
- No chance of anyone hiding anywhere?
- None whatever.
- 任何人没有机会躲在什么地方？  - 没有任何机会
Did your men search in here? Did they?
你的人搜过这里吗？搜过没？
- There was'nt people in here, so...
- Did they search in here?
- 之前这里没有人，所以... - 他们搜过这里没有？
- No.
- There's nowhere in here they could hide.
- 没有  - 这里没有可以躲藏的地方
Oh, no! Back!
噢，不！后退！
Back.
后退
Stand back, stand back from that door.
后退，后退到门那边去
You're right! It is them!
你说对了！就是他们！
Quick! Get out of it!
快！你们快跑！
No!
不！
Remain still.
不要动
You devils! You killed him! An unarmed man!
你们这群魔鬼！你们杀死了他！一个手无寸铁的人！
Get up.
起来
You are known to us.
我们知道你
And you to me.
我也知道你们
Who is in command?
这里谁说了算？
I am.
我
You will be needed.
你是需要的
What have you done with my men?
你把我的人都怎么样了
They will return.
他们会回来
They're not dead?!
他们没死
No. They are not dead. They are altered.
没，他们没死，他们只是被改造了
Altered? What have you done to them?
改造？你们对他们干了什么
They are now controlled.
他们现在是被控制的
If you do anything to my...
如果你敢伤害我的...
You will do nothing.
你什么也做不了
You will now take us to the control centre.
你将带我们去控制中心
I'll be damned...
我真该死...
Through here.
走这边
You will remain here. If you leave
you will be converted like the others.
你们待在这里．如果你们离开，你们会像其他人一样被改造
Survey party, come in, we are not receiving you, over.
调查小组，请回话，我们没有收到你们的信息．结束
Can we see the control antenna from here?
我们从这里可以看到控制天线吗？
No, Roger. It's just around that first block
just outside the main port.
不能，Roger．它正好在主舱门外面第一区域的外面
So, we have to send somebody outside so get ready...
看来，我们得派个人出去做好准备...
We have to...
我们必须...
Get back! Get back! These things are lethal!
回来！回来！这些东西是致命的fixme
None will move.
谁也不要动
If you move you will be killed.
谁动谁就没命了
What are they?! How did they get in!?
他们是什么？！怎么进来的？
Silence! We are Cybermen!
安静！我们是赛博人！
But you were all killed!
但你们都被干掉了啊！
We are going to take over the Gravitron
我们要接管"引力创"
And use it to destroy the surface of the Earth
by changing the weather.
用它来改变天气，毁灭地球表面
But that will kill everybody on the Earth.
但那会杀死地球上的所有人
Yes.
是的
You're supposed to be so advanced. Here you are,
taking your revenge like children.
还以为你们是先进文明．现在你们来了，像孩子一样搞复仇
Revenge? What is that?
复仇？那是什么？
A feeling people have...
人类的一种情感...
Feelings? Yes, we know of this weakness of yours.
情感？是的，我们知道你们的这项弱点
We are fortunate. We do not posses feelings.
我们是幸运的，我们没有情感
Then why are you here?
那你们干嘛来了?
To eliminate all dangers.
来消除所有危险
But you kill every single thing on the Earth!
但你们要杀死地球上的所有生物！
Yes. All dangers will be eliminated.
是的，这样所有危险就会消除了
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
嘿，你觉得你在干什么？
You seem to be better.
你看起来好些了
Aye, I feel myself again.
是，感觉神志清醒了些
Lie back there!
躺回去！
But I'm better!
但我好多了！
Oh, my head.
噢，我的头
Well, take it easy, mate.
好了，放松点，朋友
At least, you know it is not your McCrimmon piper.
至少，你知道不是你那个 McCrimmon 风笛手了
It had me worried though, I admit that.
它很让我忧心，我得承认
Yeah, those Cybermen have got us all worried mate.
是啊，那些赛博人让我们所有人都忧心
We see them in action before.
我们以前见过他们行动
They must have some weakness.
他们肯定有某种弱点
Well, in my day, they used to sprinkle witches with holy water.
哦，在我那时候，他们一般会朝巫婆喷洒圣水
Fat lot of use that would be on them.
那对他们用的可多了(?)
Sprinkle... Holy Water... Ben!
喷洒...圣水... Ben!
What are the Cybermen covered in?
赛博人外面穿的是什么？
As far as I know, their suit is a metal of some sort.
据我所知，他们的外套是某种金属
What about that thing on their chests? You know the part
that replaced their heart and lungs.
他们胸口那东西呢？你知道他们用那个部件替换了他们的心脏和肺
Some kind of plastic I think.
某种塑料吧，我想
I thought so. You see, it's simple.
Nail vanish remover dissolves nail vanish.
我觉得是．你看，很简单，卸甲油可以溶解指甲油
Nail vanish is a plastic. So we do what Jamie says,
we sprinkle them, see?!
指甲油也是塑料的(?)，所以我们就按 Jamie 所说的，我们喷他们，明白了吗？
No, clear as mud if you ask me.
没，跟泥巴一样，如果你问我的话
Anyway, I am going to try an experiment.
不管怎样，我打算进行一项实验
Yes, Professor.
好的，＂教授＂
Dr. Evans! I thought he was dead.
I thought that they were all dead!
Evans 医生！我以为他已经死了．我以为他们都死了！
Bet if they were by the look of it.
外表看来肯定是啊
Tell the operators in the power unit to come out.
让电力室的操作员出来
Now.
马上
All right, you can all see what is happening.
好吧，你们都看见了现在的情况
Come on out, leave the machine and don't try anything.
出来吧，离开机器，别轻举妄动
They will now take over the Gravitron power unit.
他们现在要接管＂引力创＂的电力室
Yes.
是的
But you can't send them in their without protected helmets.
但你不能让他们不带头盔就进那里去
Why?
为什么
The machine produces very intense sonic fields.
那个机器会产生非常强的声场
Without the helmets, those men will be insane in a few hours!
不带头盔的话，这些人几个小时就会疯掉的！
How many hours?
几个小时？
Twelve possibly.
大概１２小时
Then there is no problem.
那就没有问题了
Why?
为什么
Our purpose will be achieved before that.
在那之前我们的目的就应该达到了
But what about the men?
但人怎么办？
They will be disposed of.
他们会被丢弃
Now, keep your fingers crossed.
现在，交叉你的手指祈祷吧
It works!
有效！
But I still don't know what you are on about.
但我还是不懂你在搞什么
If we can sprinkle some of that on their chest units,
it might help to soften them.
如果我们能喷一些这个东西到他们胸口上，就能软化它
I get it! You mean it will clobber their controls or something.
我明白了！你是说这个能捣烂他们的控制器什么的
Yes, that's it.
对，就是这样
May the power into the vortex generators now.
将能量注入到涡流发电机上去
What is happening?
怎么回事？
There is loss of control.
这里失去控制了
Now look, we only have one chance at this.
听着，我们这事只有一次机会
When I open the door, drop down as low as you can,
当我打开门，尽量俯低身体
aim this things... at their chests and squirt like mad. Right?
将这个东西...对准他们的胸口，疯了一样猛喷，明白不?
Right.
明白
Get ready.
预备
Someone is there.
那里有人
Quick, get their chest things!
快，对准胸口！
Quick, get these things off their heads!
快，把这些东西从他们脑袋上拿下去
Come on! Quick, there isn't a moment to lose./
快来！快，我们一秒钟也不能耽搁
We got to get the Gravitron down to safe level.
我们得把＂引力创＂降到安全水平
What about those poor men?
这些可怜的家伙怎么办？
Shift them off to the medical unit, as quick as you can.
搬到医务室去，迅速
We are not receiving you. We are not receiving you.
我们收不到你的信号，我们收不到你的信号
They must have failed.
他们肯定已经失败了
Yes. We must invade now. Prepare the weapons.
是的，我们必须进攻了，准备好武器
Yes.
是的
Now listen everybody. I don't know how many more
of these Cybermen there are, /
现在，每个人都听好了．我不知道这些赛博人有多少
but our point of view we are under siege.
I'll reckon they will be back in a bit...
但我们看到的是，我们已经被包围了．我估计他们很快就会回来...
Now communications. Charlie, keep trying
to get through to Earth. Right?
现在说说通讯. Charlie, 继续尝试联系上地球，明白不？
Right, will do.
明白，马上
The rest of you, lower the armoured doors at all exits./
其他人，关上所有出口的安全门
Make up as much of that gubbins that you got, we may need it.
多造一些你们的那个小装置，我们可能需要它
Mr Hobson, how far can the probe be lowered down?
Hobson 先生，那个探测器可以降低到什么程度？
About thirty degrees.
大概３０度
That's no good.
那可不够
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Can any other part be lowered?
还有其他什么部件可以降低吗？
Well, the main coil lenses can be shifted about
without too much trouble but...
嗯，主线圈镜头可以移动，不是太费事，但是...
There's something outside there!
外面有什么东西！
What is it?
是什么？
It's a long way off.
挺远的地方
I'll come.
我就来
They can't just march in here, can they?
他们不能进到这里来吧，能吗
Not now. We've discovered how they got in.
现在不能，我们已经发现了他们是怎么进来的
Yes. They tunnelled into the storeroom.
是的，他们打隧道进了储藏室
- Doctor, Mr. Hobson, come quickly!
- What is it?
- 博士，Hobson 先生，快来！  - 什么事？
Moonbase, Moonbase
月球基地，月球基地
- They've got our wavelength. We hear you.
- You are surrounded.
- 他们知道了我们的波长．我们能听到  - 你们已经被包围了
All resistance is useless.
所有抵抗都是徒劳的
You must open the entry port.
你们必须打开入口
Let me. You're wasting your time.
We've discovered your passageway and blocked it.
我来说，你们是在浪费时间．我们已经发现了你们的通道，堵上了
- You cannot enter now.
- Resistance is useless.
- 你们现在进不来了  - 抵抗是无用的
- Can they get in?
- I don't know, but I'm not stopping to find out.
- 他们能进来吗？  - 我不知道，但我不会停止寻找的
- Get me Earth as quick as you can.
- Right.
- 赶紧给我联系地球，越快越好 - 好的
Weather Control Moon calling Earth. Come in.
天气控制中心月球站呼叫地球，请回话
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急情况！紧急情况！
There is a spaceship approaching from Earth.
有一首飞船正在接近，是地球来的
It will arrive on the lunar surface in 15 minutes.
它将在１５分钟内到达月球表面
Immediate offensive action must be taken.
必须立即展开攻击行动了
They have blocked up our way into the base.
他们堵住了我们通往基地的路
Other methods to gain entry will be tried.
将尝试其它方式进入
The machine from Earth must first be destroyed.
地球来的机器必须先被摧毁
There are 14 minutes left.
只剩１４分钟了
Understood.
明白
Transmit control signal.
传送控制信号
You will listen to me and follow my instructions.
你将听我的，服从我的指示
Here we are. I've brought some coffee to keep us awake.
来了，我拿了一些咖啡，让大家清醒清醒
- Without sugar this time, I hope?
- Of course. Don't remind me.
- 这次没有糖了吧，但愿  - 当然，别提这个
- Take some to the Doctor. He's in the Dome.
- Right.
- 给博士拿一点去，他在穹顶里面  - 好的
You will now change field co-ordinates as instructed.
你现在要按照指示改变目的地坐标
Doctor, they've spotted it on the scanner - the relief ship.
博士，可以在监视器上看到他们了 - 救援飞船
- Ben, where?   - Over here.   - Let's see.
- Ben, 哪儿？  - 在那儿   - 我们来看看
- Well?
- No doubt about it. I told you they would be on their way!
- 怎样？  - 没有疑问了，我跟你说过他们已经在来的路上了
It's not far off.
不是太远了
Far off? It's coming in now off parking orbit.
It will be down in six minutes.
太远？它已经进了降落轨道．６分钟之内就会落地了
- Don't think you ought to warn them?
- Yes, the Cybermen will be waiting for them.
- 你不觉得应该警告他们吗？ - 是啊，赛博人已经在等着他们呢
Don't worry. They've got their own warning system and weapons.
别担心．他们自己也有告警系统和武器
They'll blast the Cybermen and their spaceship
to kingdom come in about four minutes from now.
他们会把赛博人和他们的飞船炸会老家去，还有大概４分钟
Come on!
快啊
It seems to move so slowly.
它好像移动得非常慢
- What are they doing?
- Looks like they've changed direction.
- 他们在干什么啊？  - 看起来好像他们改变了方向
They've changed into an escape orbit. Follow it.
他们切换到了脱离轨道．跟住
- It's going too fast. I can't keep up with it.
- Keep trying.
- 它在加速了，我跟不住了  - 继续尝试
- I can't hold it. It's accelerating too fast.
- Look out man. You're on the sun.
- 我没法跟住了，它加速太快了  - 小心啊朋友，你已经在往太阳飞了
- That's where it's heading.
- The acceleration is.. it's gigantic!
- 它就是在往那儿飞  - 加速度..也太大了！
- Get R/T contact with the ship.
- It's no good, sir...the doppler effect...It's going too fast.
- 用无线电联系飞船  - 没用的，头儿...多普勒效应...它跑得太快了
They've had it, I'm afraid.
他们已经跑不了了，恐怕
- The sun...
- Yes.
- 太阳...  - 是的
Will somebody please tell us what it all means?
谁能不能告诉我这都是什么意思？
The rocket has been deflected towards the sun.
Nothing can save them now.
火箭已经飞偏了，在往太阳飞去．现在没谁能救他们了
- Save them? What are you talking about?
- From plunging into the sun.
- 救他们？你在说什么啊？  - 阻止他们飞向太阳
But the sun's millions of miles away.
但太阳有数百万英里之远呢
Once they get into the sun's gravity belt,
they can't change course.
一旦他们进入了太阳的引力范围，他们就改变不了航线了
It may take a week but they'll end up there.
大概需要一个星期，但他们最终会在那儿
What on earth could have caused it?
到底是什么东西导致了这个？
The rocket was deflected off course, but why, and how?
火箭当然是被导偏了，但是为什么，怎么搞得？
Deflected?
导偏？
- Yes, of course. The Gravitron!
- Have the Cybermen got a gravity weapon, do you think?
- 是了，当然，引力创！  - 赛博人有引力武器吗，你觉得？
- No, they haven't, but we have.
- You're not suggesting...?
- 不，他们没有，但我们有  - 你不是想说...？
The only one way that rocket could be deflected
into the sun... was this very room.
火箭飞被导向太阳的唯一方法...就在这个房间里！
I see what you mean.
我知道你的意思了
Of course - the Gravitron.
当然了 - 引力创
- Benson! He must...
- I said he'd been on duty too long.
- Benson! 他肯定... - 我说过他值班时间太长了
If it IS Benson...
如果的确是 Benson...
It's Evans!
是 Evans!
- He was in the medical room.
- The Cybermen have control of them again.
- 他在医务室啊 - 赛博人又控制了他们
- And the other men in there?
- They may not be affected yet.
- 那里的其他人呢？  - 他们可能还未受影响
Get down to the medical room.
Barricade the door with everything you can find.
赶紧去医务室，用所有能找到的东西把门堵上
- Keep them in there at all costs!  - Right.
- 不惜一切代价把他们控制在里面  - 好
What is he doing in there?
他在那里面做什么？
Look at the field reactors. We must get back control soon.
看看域反应器(?)，我们必须赶紧夺回控制权
He could flood half of Europe
if he keeps the Gravitron aligned with spring tides.
他可能都淹了半个欧洲了，如果他一直让引力创定在涨潮位置的话
That settles it. We'll have to rush him.
Get those weapons out.
就这样定了，我们得赶紧把他赶出去．把那些武器拿出来
Resistance is useless.
抵抗是没有用的
All further ships from Earth will be deflected.
后面再有从地球来的飞船也会转向
Open the air lock to us.
为我们打开气闸
If you do not, we shall destroy the base,
如果你们不打开，我们将摧毁基地
and you will be eliminated.
你们将会被消灭
Can you hear me?
你们能听到我？
Everything you have said
in the past half-hour has been overheard.
你们在过去半小时内说的话，全都听见了
You can hear this, too, then: we're not done yet,
and we'll fight you to the last man.
你还能听到这个：咱们没完，我们会跟你们战斗到最后一个人
- You'll never get inside this base!
- We are in it already.
- 你们永远进不了这个基地  - 我们已经进来了
They've punctured the dome!
他们打穿了穹顶！
The oxygen masks.
Everyone take a mask over there!
氧气面罩！所有人都那儿去带上氧气面罩！
I hope that we don't lose too much oxygen.
我期望我们没丧失多少氧气
- Can we patch it, do you think?
- We can try.
- 我们能补上吧，你说呢  - 我们试试
Give me a hand off with this.
给我搭把手
Doctor, I can't breathe.
博士，我不能呼吸了
Thank heavens! I can breathe again.
感谢上天！我又能呼吸了
Oh, no!
噢，不！
- What can we patch it with?
- Nothing.
- 我们能拿什么来堵？  - 没啥
Wait...
等等...
Over there.
那边
Slide it to me but don't let go of it.
把它滑给我，别放手
We have to do it in one action. No second chance. Are you ready?
我们必须一次搞定，没有第二次机会．准备好了吗？
Now!
走！
Stopped them for the moment.
暂时阻止他们了
- I wonder for how long.
- Let's have a look.
- 我在想能有多久 - 我们看看吧
Polly! Are you all right?
Polly！你没事吧？
Yes.
是的
- Where's that air coming from?
- Reserve tanks of oxygen.
- 那些空气哪里来的？ - 预备的氧气瓶
- Why couldn't we have had those before?
- And lose all our oxygen?
- 之前为什么没有？ - 你是说失去我们所有的氧气？
I see.
我明白了
- It's so quiet!  - Yes, it is, isn't it?
- 好安静啊！  - 是的，真安静，是吧？
The Gravitron's stopped!
引力创停掉了！
Quick. Before he comes to. Ben! Jamie!
快！在他醒过来之前. Ben! Jamie!
Joe!
We've barricaded the sick bay with half the chairs and tables in the base, but it won’t hold them for ever.
我们堵住了医务室，用了基地半数的椅子和桌子，但没法永远挡住他们
- Well done. - Here's another one for you.
- 干得好  - 这个你来
- What do we do with him, Doctor?
- That's your problem.
- 我们拿他怎么办，博士  - 那是你的事
Just make sure he doesn’t come back here for a while.
只是要确保短时间内他不能回到这里来
I’ll be after a job as a copper when I get
back to 1966!
等我回到1966年，我要去找个当警察的职业干干
Mr Hobson, I've got an idea.
Hobson 先生，我有了个想法
- Doctor, what do you make of this?
- Made by a laser beam, I think.
- 博士，你觉得这是怎么造成的  - 激光束，我想是
- Is there anything known to science the Cybermen haven't got?
- They haven’t got a Gravitron. Or they wouldn't be after yours.
科学上已知的东西里面有没有什么赛博人没掌握的？
他们还没有引力创，否则他们不会来抢你们的
We'll have to stand guard here
with their cyberguns.
Not much use. They're getting
reinforcements. Looks like another spaceship.
没多大用. 他们有了增援. 看样子是又来一艘飞船
Just there.
就在那儿
Another one!
又来一个！
We have brought
reinforcements with other weapons.
我们带来了增援和其它武器
You have one chance.
You must open the entry port.
你们有一次机会. 你们必须打开入口
You cannot stop us now.
You will all be completely destroyed.
现在你们阻挡不了我们了. 你们全部都会被完全消灭
- What does he mean, other weapons?
- We'll soon find out. You stay here. I must report this to Mr. Hobson.
他什么意思，“其它武器”？
我们很快就能弄清楚. 你在这里待着. 我必须向 Hobson 先生报告这个
I shall count to ten.
我将数到十
If you still stupidly remain silent, we shall fire.
如果你们仍然愚蠢地保持沉默，我们将开火
One...
一
- Hurry! They've got another weapon. They're going to ...
- Yes, I know. There it is.
- 快！他们有了另外一个武器，他们要...
- 是的，我知道，就在那儿
Everybody take cover. Get down, all of you! Doctor!
所有人都躲起来. 你们全都蹲下！博士！
- Is the Gravitron still switched on?  - Yes.
- 引力创还开着吗？  - 是的
Then I shall certainly stay here.
那我就一定还得留在这里
.. nine, ten... Fire!
...九，十...开火！
Again. Fire.
再来，开火！
- What happened?
- It just deflected over the dome.
- 什么情况？ - 它刚才转弯从穹顶上飞过去了
- Are you all right?  - Yes.
- 你没事吧？  - 没事
- The Gravitron deflected it. The force field.
- Yes. And that gives me an idea.
- 引力创弹歪了它，力场的作用  - 是的，这给了我一个主意
What are they doing now?
他们现在在干什么？
They're packing it away.
他们在收拾走人
What will they cook up next?
他们下一步想炮制什么？
How far down can this be aimed? Can it be
brought to bear on the surface of the moon?
这个最低可以瞄准哪里？能否牵引到对准月球表面？
- I see!  - Well...
- 我明白了  - 这个...
- Has it ever been tried?  - No, but we shall try.
- 试过这样吗？  - 没，但我们得试试
- With Evans gone, the Gravitron is all yours.
- Je m'en occupe!
- 现在 Evans 走了，引力创归你了 - 我会处理好的（法语）
Any further down, and the field may affect the base.
再低一点，力场就会影响基地了
- What does that matter now?
- Ah, I suppose you're right.
- 到现在了，那又有什么关系   - 啊，我想你是对的
- Get someone to stand by that window
and relay instructions direct to Benoit.
- Right!
找个人站到那个窗户旁边，将指令转述给 Benoit
- He's ready.  - Start moving the probe down.
- 他就绪了  - 开始向下移动探测器
- That's as far as it will go.
- What?
- 最多也就能到这个位置了
- 什么？
But it's way over their heads.
但高出他们的头太多了
There's one chance. We'll try bringing it down by hand.
只有一次机会，我们得用手把它拉下来
- Is this still switched off?
- No, No.. Yes, of course.
- 这个仍然是关着的吗？   - 不，不，对了，当然
- It won't go.
- All your weight. Once more.
- 它没动  - 用上全部力气，再来一次
- It's no use. It won't shift.
- Ah, stupid of me! Of course it won't!
- 没用，它一动不动  - 啊，我真蠢，当然它不会动了
- Why?
- The angular cut-out. It's obvious!
- 为什么？  - 角度阻断器，很显然
There's got to be a safety cut-out
on the angle of the probe.
探测器的角度必须得有一个安全阻断器
Otherwise, it might affect the whole base.
否则，它就会影响整个基地
That's done it. Stand back. Benoit can do it now.
这下可以了．往后站．Benoit 现在可以操作了
Switch on!
现在启动！
Well, that's taken care of the Cybermen!
好了，它可以照料赛博人了
We've got to get this Gravitron in operation as fast as we can!
我们得尽快让引力创重新运转起来！
- I'm so sorry we damaged it.  - What? Oh, yes...
- 很抱歉我们毁坏了它  - 什么？噢，是的...
Nils, rig up a temporary aerial. Call up Space Control.
Nils, 架一个临时天线，联系控制中心
Tell Rinberg we'll be operational in about two hours.
It's the best we can do.
告诉 Rinberg 我们将在大约两小时后恢复运作．最好我们也就能这样了
Two hours! That's all we've got to
get the world's weather under control again.
两小时，那是我们能有的时间，要让地球天气重新处于掌控之中
Benoit, take charge of your side.
And, Doctor... What the...
Benoit, 负责你那边的事情．而博士...怎么...
It's just as well. We've enough madmen here already!
这样也行吧，我们这里疯子已经够多了
I want to see your first weather plot in two minutes!
我期望在两分钟之内见到你的天气运行图
Come on, boys.
加油，小伙子们
Doctor, look.
博士，看
- Could that be them?  - Possibly.
- 会是他们吗？  - 很可能
And I hope it's the last we see of them.
我期望这是我最后一次看见他们
There we are. In perfect flight.
好啦，进入完美的飞行了
- Yes, and look what happened last time!
- Just a bumpy landing. It won't happen again.
- 是啊，看看上次都发生了什么！
- 只是着陆有点颠簸，不会再发生了
- I know.
- What you're up now?
- 我知道  - 你又在干什么？
- Let's have a look at the Time Scanner. - The what?
- 我们来看看时间扫描仪  - 看什么？
The Time Scanner. Instead of showing where we are,
it gives you a glimpse of the future.
时间扫描仪．不是显示我们在哪儿，而是让你瞥一眼未来
The second sight? Very dangerous.
第二视觉？这太危险了
Nonsense! I haven't used it very much.
It's not very reliable, as you can see.
胡说！我用它的次数不多，它不是太可靠，你们可以看到
Doctor...
博士...
Look!
快看！